Guide to the Lesly Lempert Collection, 1987-1994.
Lempert, Lesly Collection
- Series I. Periodicals
  - Jerusalem Papers on Peace Problems, September 1974--December 1974 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    Volume/Number: 8, 10
  - (Jerusalem Papers on Peace Problems): United States-Israel Relations, 1967-1973: A Study in the Convergence and Divergence of Interests, September, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    Producer: Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Shlomo Slonim
  - (Jerusalem Papers on Peace Problems): The Limits of Alliance: America, Europe, and The Middle East, December, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    Producer: Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Linda B. Miller
  - Freedom of Expression in the United Kingdom, March, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    Producer: Helsinki Watch, Fund for Free Expression, Human Rights Watch
  - [Background Information] (document, letter, pamphlet), July, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    Producer: Hotline for Victims of Violence
  - Bureaucracy of Repression: The Iraqi Government in Its Own Words, February, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    Producer: Human Rights Watch/Middle East
  - The Bush Administration's Record on Human Rights in 1989 (v. 2, photocopy, pages 176-199), January, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    Producer: Human Rights Watch
  - Human Rights Watch World Report 1993: Events of 1992, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    Volume/Number: 1--2
  - Human Rights Watch World Report: An Annual Review of the Bush Administration's Policy on Human Rights Worldwide (Middle East Watch Overview, p. 293-356), January, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Middle East Watch Board of Directors, January, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Press Release, January 10, 1990; April 9, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - (Press Release): Human Rights Watch Decries the Bush Administration's Double Standard, January 10, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - (Press Release): Government of Morocco Prevents Demonstration by Women's Rights Groups Protesting Sexual Harassment, April 9, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Publications from Human Rights Watch, September, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Quarterly Newsletter, Spring 1991--Summer 1992 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Special Issue: Accountability for Past Human Rights Abuses, December, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Prison Conditions: In Egypt, February, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    Producer: Human Rights Watch, Middle East Watch
  - Free Expression, Rule of Law Imperiled in Egypt by Apostasy Declaration of Muslim Cleric, July 10, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Prison Conditions: In Israel and the Occupied Territories: A Middle East Watch Report, April, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 213 A)
  - Critique: Review of the Department of State's Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 1987, 1989, June. 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 213 A)
    Producer: Human Rights Watch, Lawyers Committee for Human Rights
  - Response to "B'Tselem Report Regarding Adminstrative Detention, October 29, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    Producer: Information Branch
  - Arabs in Israel, October 14, 1990--December, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    Producer: Institute for Arab-Jewish Affairs (IAJA), Histadrut
    Volume/Number: 1.1--1.3, 1.6--1.23
  - Arabs in Israel, January, 1992--October 1993 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    Volume/Number: 1.24--1.26, 2.2--2.5, 2.7, 2.10--2.12, 3.2, 3.7
  - Images and Reality: Palestinian Women under Occupation and in the Diaspora, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    Producer: Institute for Arab Women's Studies, Inc., IAWS Monograph Series Women of Palestine
  - Palestine Refugees and the Process, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    Producer: Institute for Palestine Studies
  - The Palestinian-Israeli Peace Agreement: A Documentary Record, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 218 A)
  - U.S. Official Statements: The Status of Jerusalem, July, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 218 B)
    Producer: Institute for Palestine Studies, Jody Boudreault (Editor), Yasser Salaam (Editor)
  - The Economic Viability of a Palestinian State, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 218 B)
    Producer: Institute for Palestine Studies, George T. Abed
  - Arab Local Government in Israel, June, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    Producer: International Center for Peace in the Middle East, Majid Al-Haj, Henry Rosenfeld
  - The Condition and Status of the Arabs in Israel, June, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    Producer: International Center for Peace in the Middle East, (multiple authors)
  - Israel Press Briefs, March/April 1987--May 1990 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    Producer: International Center for Peace in the Middle East
    Volume/Number: 52, 62, 64--65, 67, 69, 72
  - Jewish Settlement in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Social Welfare Services for Israel's Arab Population, December, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    Producer: International Center for Peace in the Middle East, Aziz Haidar
  - Israel as a Nation-State and the Problem of the Arab Minority: In Search of a Status, December, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    Producer: International Center for Peace in the Middle East, Claude Klein
  - Children of the Uprising, 1988; photocopy, 5 leaves (Box 5, Folder 224)
    Producer: International Children's Rights Monitor
  - Inquiry into the Israeli Military Court System in the Occupied West Bank and Gaza, [December 1989] (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Producer: International Commission of Jurists, (multiple authors)
  - Civilian Administration in the Occupied West Bank: Analysis of Israeli Military Government, January, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Producer: International Commission of Jurists
  - Press Release: ICJ Protests Threatened Illegal Reprisal in the Occupied West Bank, March 20, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - (Update): Re: ICJ Press Release About Planned Ramallah Demolition, May 7, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Torture and Intimidation in the West Bank: The Case of al-Fara'a Prison, [1984?] (Box 5, Folder 227)
    Producer: International Commission of Jurists, Law in the Service of Man
  - Summary of the Geneva Conventions of August 12, 1949 and their Additional Protocols, June, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    Producer: International Committee of the Red Cross
  - ICCP Newsletter, June 9, 1989--January 20, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    Producer: International Coordinating Committee for NGO's on the Question of Palestine (ICCP)
    Volume/Number: 17, 22--23, 26, 29--31, 33, 35--39
  - ICCP Newsletter: Special Issue: Palestinian Prisoners in the Uprising, [?]; photocopy, 9 pages (Box 5, Folder 230)
    Producer: International Coordinating Committee for NGOs on the Question of Palestine (ICCP)
  - Urgent Appeal: An Amendment to the Israel's Prevention of Terrorism Ordinance of 1948 Aimed at Stopping the Transfer of Funds from "Terrorist Organizations" to Arab Associations, May 25, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - The Givati Protocols, [1988?]; translation, 26 leaves (Box 5, Folder 232)
    Producer: International Jewish Peace Union NY, (multiple editors), Lila Roccas (translator)
  - Reshumot, March 25,1992--May 22, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    Producer: Israel
  - (Reshumot): Sefer ha-huqim: 1391, March 25, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - (Reshumot): Sefer ha-huqim: 1396, April 14, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - (Reshumot): ha-tsa'ot hoq: 1930, May 22, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Va'adat-he-haqirah…: din-ve-heshbon, heleq rishon, October, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Background Information on IPCRI and Work Plan for 1992, January, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    Producer: Israel/Palestine Center for Research and Information (IPCRI)
  - I.P.C.R.I. News, Autumn 1990--Summer 1995 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Israel/Palestine Issue in Conflict: Issues for Cooperation: Water Conflict or Cooperation, May, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    Producer: Israel/Palestine Center for Research and Information (IPCRI), George Baskin
    Volume/Number: 1.2
  - Israeli-Palestinian Peace Documentation Series, June, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Research Report, 1990--1991 (Box 5, Folder 239)
    Producer: Israel Institute of Applied Social Research, Haya Gratch
  - The Other Israel: Newsletter of the Israeli Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace, April-May 1989--November-December 1994, April 1989--December 1994 (Box 5, Folder 240)
    Producer: Israeli Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace
    Volume/Number: 36, 48. 54/55, 62/63--64
  - The Myth of the Status Quo, Spring, 1990; photocopy, p. 25-28, 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 241)
    Producer: Israeli Democracy
  - Report: Human Rights Violations during the Palestinian Uprising, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    Producer: Israeli League for Human and Civil Rights
  - Israeli Obstacles: to Economic Development in the Occupied Palestinian Territories, November, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    Producer: Jerusalem Media and Communication Centre
  - Lessons of Occupation: Palestinian Higher Education During the Uprising, May, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - No Exit: Israel's Curfew Policy in the Occupied Palestinian Territories, June, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Palestinian Education: A Threat to Israel's Security? [Briefing Paper], August, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Reporting Harassment: Israeli Restrictions of Press Freedom In the West Bank and Gaza Strip, August, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Soviet Jewish Immigration and Isralei Settlement in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, December, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Palestinian Education: A Threat to Israel's Security?: The Israeli Policy of School Closures in the Occupied West Bank and Gaza Strip, December 1987--January 1989 (Box 5, Folder 248 A)
  - [Articles pertaining to MK Rehavam Ze'evi], February 3, 1991--February 6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - (Article): Shamir Plan to Bring Ze'evi Into Cabinet Raises Political Storm, February 3, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
    Producer: Michal Yudelman, David Makovsky, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Concern in Likud over Ze'evi appointment; Knesset OK expected, February 4, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - (Article): The Ze'evi compromise, February 4, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - (Article): PM expects all ministers to back Ze'evi, February 5, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
    Producer: Michal Yudelman, Asher Wallfish, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): MKs approve Ze'evi as cabinet minister by vote of 61-54, February 6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 249)
    Producer: Asher Wallfish, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Controversial character in cabinet, [?] (Box 5, Folder 249)
    Producer: Michal Yudelman, Jerusalem Post
  - [Miscellaneous articles from The Jerusalem Post, May 30, 1984--November 20, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - (Article): Ford Grant, May 30, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 250)
    Producer: Zvi Kesse, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Steinsaltz, August 18, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - (Article): Controversial UN Resolution 242, A Quarter-Century After, November 20, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 250)
    Producer: Yehuda Z. Blum, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): History-making Arab Judge, [?] (Box 5, Folder 250)
    Producer: David Rudge, Jerusalem Post
  - [Typescripts of Jerusalem Post Articles], April 11, 1991--September 25, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Jerusalem Post, (various authors)
  - (Article): Druse MK's Son Arrested for Refusing IDF Service, April 11, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Colonel Meir demoted in 'Limb-breaking' trial, April 24, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Bradley Burston, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Arab Woman Gives Birth in Car at IDF Roadblock, June 5, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Jon Immanuel, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): IDF Lawyer's to Let Meir's Sentence Stand Unchallenged, June 5, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Who Gives the Orders, Anyway?, June 6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Soldiers Make Nablus Residents Sweep Road After Stoning, June 6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Soldiers Filed Nearly 7,000 Complaints, 45% Justified, June 6, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Hamas: Missing Its Chance?, June 7, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Arab Workers Save Moshavnik from Stabber, June 17, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Four IDF NCOs to be Tried for Attacking Area Arabs, June 20, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Arab Rescues Woman Soldier from Attacker, June 26, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Jerusalem Post, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Policemen Fired for Abusing Office, June 26, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Michael Rotem, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Rookie Policemen Sparks Beating of Druse Officers, June 30, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Harish Foils Plan for Haredi Land Giveaway, July 1, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Beduin Enlistment Tripled; Seen as Reaction to Intifada, July 3, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Likud and Right Riding Crest of Strong Support, Poll Finds, July 7, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Hanoch Smith, Rafi Smith, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): President Urges Inquiry into Justice System, July 9, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    Producer: Greer Fay Cashman, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Play Censorship Changed, July 24, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): More Officer Trials Possible on Intifada, September 15, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - (Article): Hanan Ashrawi speaks out: We didn't support coup, [August 26, 1991]; photocopy (Box 5, Folder 251 A)
  - (Article): People who Live in Glass Houses, June 21 1990 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
    Producer: David Forman, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article):Peace-Seekers Among the Palestinians, August 2 1990 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article):A Plague on all your Houses, October 25 1990 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article):Bankruptcy in the Peace Movement, November 7 1990 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article):Words can Demoralize and Destroy, November 29 1990 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article): It's Still a Man's World, January 10 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article): Don't Turn Your Back on us, Yossi, February 19 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - (Article): A Jewish State or a State of Jews?, March 18 1991 (Box 5, Folder 251 B)
  - Daily Report from the Occupied Territories, December 6, 1991; transmission, 8 leaves (Box 5, Folder 252)
    Producer: Jerusalem Press
  - The Lack of Family Visits for Palestinian Prisoners in Israel, August 14, 1991; transmission, 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 253)
    Producer: Jerusalem Press Service
  - President Clinton: Middle East Peace Signing Ceremony for the Israeli-PLO Accord, September 13 1993 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - National Press Club Lunch: Speaker Yasser Arafat, Chrm, PLO, September 14 1993 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - The Worldly Jerusalem, December 26, 1991; photocopy, 1 page (Box 5, Folder 254)
    Producer: Jerusalem Report
  - [Arab Citizens in the Israeli Economy], [January 1995]; typescript, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 255)
    Producer: Jewish-Arab Center for Economic Development
  - McCloskey calls on PLO to maintain moderation despite loss, January 5, 1985, January 16, 1985; transmission, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 256)
    Producer: Jordan Times
  - [Letter of Transmittal], January 16, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    Producer: Paul N. McCloskey, Jr.
  - Newsletter, August 1990--December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 257)
    Producer: Kav la-'Oved (Workers' Hotline)
  - [Background Information], [?] (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - SEIU Civil and Human Rights Conference Says "No" to Loan Guarantees for Israel, February 23, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 258)
    Producer: Labor Committee on the Middle East
  - Human Rights Violations in the West Bank: In Their Own Words, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 259)
    Producer: Law in the Service of Man, Commission of the Churches on International Affairs World Council of Churches
  - Advocay Alert #4: Rule of Law Under Threat in Gaza and Jericho, February 16, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    Producer: Lawyers Committee for Human Rights
  - Briefing Paper, May 7, 1992, February 23, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - (Briefing Paper): Lawyers and the Military Justice System of the Israeli-Occupied Territories, May 7, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - (For Immediate Release): Lawyers and the Military Justice System of the Israeli-Occupied Territories, May 7, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - (Briefing Paper): A Continuing Cause for Concern: The Military Justice System of the Israeli-Occupied Territories, February 23, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Critique: Review of the U.S. Department of State's Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 1991: Israeli-Occupied Territories, [1991?] (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - The Lack of Family Visits for Palestinian Prisoners in Israel, July 30, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Raji Sourani-Gaza Strip, February, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    Producer: Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Lawyer to Lawyer Network
  - The Treatment of Alleged Collaborators and Other Security Detainees in Kuwait, August 9, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - An Examination of Human Rights Workers and Lawyers from the West Bank and Gaza and Conditions of Detention at Ketziot, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 265 A)
  - Global Viewpoints Forum: Water Resources: Israeli and Palestinian Concerns, May 2, 1990; transcript, 34 leaves (Box 5, Folder 266)
    Producer: Legacy International, Israel Palestine Center for Research and Information (IPCRI)
  - Israel & Palestine Political Report, March-April 1989--November-December 1994, March 1989--December 1994 (Box 5, Folder 267)
    Producer: MAGELAN, Association Mashrek Developpement
    Volume/Number: 149, 156, 166, 187
  - Agreement Reached in Hunger Strike, October 16, 1992; photocopy, 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 268)
    Producer: Mandela Institute
  - Status Report, October 12, 1992; photocopy, 1 page (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Summary Activity of the Jailed Movement Strike covering events from 30 September-4 October 1992, September 30, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Proposal for Emergency Support: Ansar International Tour, [1992?]; photocopy, 1 page (Box 5, Folder 271)
    Producer: Al-Masrah
  - [Background Information], [1988?] (Box 5, Folder 272)
    Producer: Middle East Childrens Alliance
  - Permanent Medical Clinic in Kalandia Camp: Proposal to Operation California, January 12, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, October 1993--July 1994 (Box 5, Folder 274)
    Producer: Middle East Data Center, Israel Shahak (translator)
    Volume/Number: 5.8--6.2, 6.6--6.7
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, December 1994--December 1995 (Box 5, Folder 275)
    Volume/Number: 6.12--7.1, 7.4, 7.7--7.8, 7.10--7.12
  - Middle East International, June 9, 1989--March 16, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    Producer: Middle East International
    Volume/Number: 352, 365, 369, 371
  - Reports James Baker Should Read, May 31, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - New Outlook, August 1986--May 1988 (Box 6, Folder 278)
    Producer: Middle East Monthly, Chaim Shur (editor-in-chief)
    Volume/Number: 260, 265/266--267, 271/272, 279/280--281
  - New Outlook, June 1988--November/December 1989 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    Volume/Number: 282--286, 294--297/298
  - New Outlook, January/February 1990--April/May 1991 (Box 6, Folder 280)
    Volume/Number: 299/300--304, 306--307, 310/311--314/315
  - New Outlook, June/July/August 1991--January/February 1993 (final issue), June--February 1993 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    Volume/Number: 316/318--335/336
  - New Outlook Newservice, July 17, 1990--June 3, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 282)
    Producer: Middle East Monthly
    Volume/Number: 5, 13, 16, 23
  - Middle East Report, May/June 1989--November/December 1994 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Producer: Middle East Research and Information Project
    Volume/Number: 158, 164/165, 187/188, 191
  - (Middle East Report): Palestine and Israel in the US Arena, May/June 1989 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Volume/Number: 158
  - (Middle East Report): Intifada Year Three, May/June-July/August 1990 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Volume/Number: 164/165
  - (Middle East Report): Gender & Politics: Are the Changes for the Better?, November/December 1991 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Volume/Number: 173
  - (Middle East Report): Humanitarian Intervention and North-South Politics in the 90's, March-April/May-June 1994 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Volume/Number: 187/188
  - (Middle East Report): Iran's Revolutionary Impasse, November/December 1994 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    Volume/Number: 191
  - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 283a)
    Producer: Palestine-Israel Journal of Politics, Economics and Culture
    Volume/Number: 2.2, 2.5
  - (Palestine-Israel Journal): Our Jerusalem, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 283a)
    Volume/Number: 2.2
  - (Palestine-Israel Journal): Oslo: A Crisis Examined, Winter 1995 (Box 6, Folder 283a)
    Volume/Number: 2.5
  - A Victory Turned Sour: Human Rights in Kuwait Since Liberation, September, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    Producer: Middle East Watch, Human Rights Watch
  - Algeria: Lawyer Brahim Taouti, Active in Human Rights, Gets 3-Year Sentence; Two U.S.-Based Rights Groups Urge his Release, May 11, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 285)
    Producer: Middle East Watch, Lawyers Committee for Human Rights
  - Board Meeting, February 17, 1993: Agenda, February 17, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    Producer: Middle East Watch
  - (Attached): Recent Press Releases, February 17, 1993--February 24, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - (Attached): Statements on Israeli Deportations, December 16, 1992--February 4, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Egypt: Trials of Civilians in Military Courts Violate International Law: Executions Continue, No Appeal of Death Sentences to Higher Court, July, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Egyptian Government Moves to Dissolve Prominent Arab Women's Organization, September, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - Ex-Political Prisoners Barred from Leaving Morocco Despite Liberaliation of Passport Policies, September, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Human Rights Abuses in Algeria: No One is Spared, January, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Human Rights Conditions in the Israeli-Occupied West Bank and Gaza Strip, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Human Rights Conditions in the Middle East in 1993: Middle East Watch Section of the Human Rights Watch World Report 1994, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Iran: Political Dissidents, Held for Over a Year, are Reportedly Sentenced, September 3, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Israel's Truth-Telling without Accountability: Inquest Faults Police in Killings at Jerusalem Holy Sit But Judge Orders No Charges, September, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - The Israeli Army and the Intifada: Policies that Contribute to the Killings, August, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Israel Indicates it will Permit One West Bank University to Reopen, May 17, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - Israeli Interrogation Methods Under Fire After Death of Detained Palestinian, March, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Palestinian Deportees Continue to Suffer from Poor Conditions in Lebanon Camp, August, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Press Release, February 2, 1992--July 28, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Human Rights Watch Applauds Canada's Decision to Grant a Saudi Feminist Political Asylum, February 2, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Middle East Watch Condemns Reported Mass Summary Deportations of Palestinians (stapled with December 17 and 18, 1992), December 16, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Middle East Watch Urges U.S. to Take the Lead in Denouncing Israel's Mass Deportation of Palestinians, December 17, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Israel Still Refuses to Provide Names of Deportees, December 18, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Middle East Watch Mission to Lebanon finds Conditions at Palestinian Deportees Camp Disastrous; MEW again Urges Israel to Repartriate Deportees, January 12, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Middle East Watch Condemns Israeli Court Ruling on Deportations, January 23, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - (Press Release): Middle East Watch Condemns Targeting of Civilians by Israeli Forces and Lebanese Guerrillas, July 28, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 299)